Guide to the Stanford Family Library Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford family library collection
1795-1902
1834-1897
SC0010
Stanford family.
16 Linear feet
A sampling of the books contained in the libraries of Jane Lathrop Stanford, Leland Stanford, and their son, Leland Stanford, Jr. Included are books inscribed by Mrs. Stanford to Leland, Jr., books annotated by Leland, Jr., and books of Thomas Welton Stanford (brother of Leland Stanford). Included are Bibles, religious publications, children's stories, a number of adventure series for boys, history books, travel essays, tourist guides, and novels.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, Stanford Museum, 1950.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
A sampling of the books contained in the libraries of Jane Lathrop Stanford, Leland Stanford, and their son, Leland Stanford, Jr. Included are books inscribed by Mrs. Stanford to Leland, Jr., books annotated by Leland, Jr., and books of Thomas Welton Stanford (brother of Leland Stanford). Included are Bibles, religious publications, children's stories, a number of adventure series for boys, history books, travel essays, tourist guides, and novels.
Access Terms
Stanford family.; Stanford, Jane Lathrop, 1828-1905.; Stanford, Leland, 1824-1893.; Stanford, Leland, 1868-1884.; Stanford, Thomas Welton, 1832-1918.; Private libraries
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - "Tommy Hickup; or, A Pair of Black Eyes" by Rosa Abbott. Boston: Lee & Shepard, 1870 (Box 1)
  - "Upside Down; or Will and Work" by Rosa Abbott. Boston: Lee & Shepard, 1870 (Box 1)
  - "The Wolf-Boy of China; or Incidents and Adventures in the Life of Lyu-Payo. New Edition" by William Dalton. London: E. Marlborough & Co., undated (Box 1)
  - "A Theoretical and Practical Grammar of the French Tongue. 31st edition" by M. De Levizac. Paris: Baudry's European Library, undated (Box 1)
  - "Imitation of Christ" by Thomas A. Kempis, undated (Box 1)
  - "Biblioteca de Educacion. Historia Moderna. Tomo II." by Don Antonio Rosales (translator). Madrid: Boix, 1844 (Box 1)
  - "A Word to Christian Teachers and Students for the Ministry, 3rd edition" by Samuel B. Schieffelin. New York: Board of Publication of the Reformed Church in America, 1878 (Box 1)
  - "The Child's First History of Rome, New Edition" by Miss (?) Sewell. London: Longmans, Green and Co., 1849 (Box 1)
  - "Around the World in Eighty Days" by Jules Verne. Translated by Geo. M. Towle. Boston: James R. Osgood and Company, Late Ticknor & Fields, and Fields, Osgood, & Co., 1874 (Box 1)
  - "Here A Little and There A Little: Or, Scripture Facts" Philadelphia: Claxton, Remsen & Haffelfinger, 1877 (Box 2)
  - "The Nursery, A Magazine for the Youngest Readers" Boston: John L. Shorey (stereotyped and printed by Rand, Avery, & Co.), 1870 (Box 2)
    Bound book includes two volumes of the magazine
  - "Frank at Don Carlos' Racho. The Rocky Mountain Series." by Harrry Castlemon. Philadelphia: Porter & Coates (and) Cincinnati, Ohio: R. W. Carroll & Co., 1871 (Box 2)
  - "History of My Pets" by Grace Greenwood. Boston: James R. Osgood and Company, Late Ticknor & Fields, and Fields Osgood & Co., 1871 (Box 2)
  - "Recollections of My Childhood and Other Stories" by Grace Greenwood. Boston: James R. Osgood and Company, Late Ticknor & Fields, and Fields Osgood & Co., 1871 (Box 2)
  - "Appletons' School Readers, the Fourth Reader" by William T. Harris, Andrew J. Rickoff and Mark Bailey. New York, Boston and Chicago: D. Appleton and Company, 1878 (Box 2)
  - "The Mission of the Black Rifle; or, On the Trail. The Forest Glen Series" by Elijah Kellogg. Boston: Lee & Shepard (and) New York: Charles T. Dillingham, 1876 (Box 2)
  - "The English Reader: Or, Pieces in Prose and Verse, from the Best Writers; Designed to Assist Young Persons to Read with Propriety and Effect; Improve Their Language and Sentiments; and to Inculcate the most Important Principles of Piety and Virtue. With a Few Preliminary Observations on the Principles of Good Reading." by Lindley Murray. Elizabeth Town, NJ: T. O. Sayre (stereotyped by H. and H. Wallis, New York), 1834 (Box 2)
  - "Studien Und Plaudereien. First Series, Eight Edition Revised with Grammatical Tables" by Sigmon M. Stern. New York: Henry Hold and Company (and) F. W. Christern (and) Boston: Carl Schenhof, 1879 (Box 2)
  - "Peep-Show. Amusement and Instruction for the Young. With 300 Pictures and a Coloured Frontspiece (Red Binding) London: Strahan & Co. (and) New York: Lovell, Adam & Company, circa 1876 (Box 3)
  - "Peep-Show. Amusement and Instruction for the Young. With 330 (Blue Binding) London: Strahan & Co. (and) New York: Thomas Nelson & Sons, circa 1875 (Box 3)
  - "Wild Life Under the Equator. Narrated for Young People." by Paul Du Chaillu. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1875 (Box 3)
  - "Life and Times of Apollonius of Tyana. Rendered into English from the Greek of Philostratus the Elder. Stanford University Publications University Series Language and Literature Volume II Number 1" by Charles P. Eells. Stanford, California: Stanford University Press, 1923 (Box 3)
  - "Cast Away in the Cold: An Old Man's Story of a Young Man's Adventures, As Related by Captain Hohn Hardy, Mariner" by Isaac I. Hayes. Boston: lee and Shepard (and) New York: Charles T. Dillingham, 1877 (Box 3)
  - "Out of Darkness Into Light" by Mary A. Lathbury. Boston: D. Lothrop and Company, 1878 (Box 3)
  - "Holy Bible Containing Old and new Teftaments Tranflated out of the Original Tongues: And with the Former Translations Diligently Compared and Revifed, by His Majesty's Special Command. Appointed to be Read in Churches. To the Most High and Mighty Prince James, by teh Grace of God, King of Great Britain, France and Ireland, Defender of the Faith, &c." Oxford: clarendon Press, William Jackson and William Dawson, Printers to the University: And fold at the Oxford Bible warehoufe, in Paternofter Row, London, 1795 (Box 4)
  - "The Fifth Reader" by E. A. Sheldon. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, Successors to Scribner, Armstrong & Co., 1875 (Box 4)
  - "Sammlung historisch-beruhmter Autographen, oder Facsimiles von Handschriften ausgezeichneter Personen alter und neuer Zeit. Erste Serie." Stuggart: Bechers., 1846 (Box 5)
  - "The Child's Picture Book of Wild Animals." London: George Routledge & Sons (and) printed by J. Ogden and Co., undated (Box 5)
  - "The Pulpit Reporter: A Religious Volume, Containing Over Sixty Sermons, Recently Delivered by Eminent Living Divines, in Various Parts of the United States. Also: Portraits and Biographical Sketches of Several Prominent Living Clergymen; Skeleton Sermons, etc." New York: Holbrook, Buckingham & company, 1850 (Box 5)
    a collection of weekly pamphlets published Dec. 1 1849 - June 1, 1850
  - "Vues de Versailles. Le Chateau, Le Parc, Le Petit et Le Grand Trianon", undated (Box 5)
  - "Man on the Ocean. A Book About Boats and Ships." by R. M. Ballantyne. London, Edinburgh and New York: T. Nelson and Sons, 1874 (Box 6)
  - "Of the Imitation of Christ. Four Books by Thomas A. Kempis with an Introduction by the Rev. Frederic W. Farrar." by Thomas A. Kempis. New York: E. P. Dutton & Company, 1891 (Box 6)
  - "The Flag of Distress: A Tale of the South Sea (illustrated)" by Capt. Maine Reid. New York: James Miller, 1878 (Box 6)
  - "A Smaller History of Greece, From the Earliest Time to the Roman Conquest" by William Smith. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1858 (Box 6)
  - "On the Track" by Jules Verne. London: Ward, Lock and Tyler, circa 1880 (Box 6)
  - "The English at the North Pole. Voyages and Adventures of Captain Hatteras. The Jules Verne Library." by Jules Verne. London: Ward, Lock & Tyler, circa 1880 (Box 6)
  - "The Steam House (Part II): Tigers and Traitors. Illustrated." by Jules Verne. Translated by Agnes D. Kingston. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1881 (Box 6)
  - "A Little Album Containing the Most Interesting Views of Our City" Venise: Candiani & Sondermann Verres artistiques-Mosaiques, undated (Box 7)
  - "Album of the Lakes of Killarney. 12 Views." by W. Lawrence. Dublin: W. Lawrence, Photographer, Publisher, undated (Box 7)
  - "Album Von Muchen" Frankfurt: Ph. Frey & Co., undated (Box 7)
  - "Neuestes Rhein Panorama Don Ph. Fren & Co. in Frankfurt" Frankfurt: Fren & Co., undated (Box 7)
  - "Ricordo Di Firenze" Venezia: C. Kirchmayr & F. Scozzi, undated (Box 7)
  - "Ricordo Di Milano" Milano: Flli Tensi-Editori, undated (Box 7)
  - "Ricordo Di Roma. I." Roma: Luigi Monti. Edicola Piazza Colonna., undated (Box 7)
  - "Ricordo Di Roma. II." Roma: Luigi Monti. Edicola Piazza Colonna., undated (Box 7)
  - "Ricordo Di Venezia" Trieste (and) Venezia: Presso Colombo Coen e Figlio Editori, 1875 or later (Box 7)
  - "Ricordo Di. Venezia. N. 1" Venezia: C. Kirchmayr & F. Scozzi, undated (Box 7)
  - "Ricordo Di. Venezia. N. 2" Venezia: C. Kirchmayr & F. Scozzi, undated (Box 7)
  - "Ricordo Di. Venezia. N. 3" Venezia: C. Kirchmayr & F. Scozzi, undated (Box 7)
  - "Souvenir de L'Oberland Bernois", undated (Box 7)
  - "Souvenir de Lucerne" Lucerne: C, F. P. Rell, undated (Box 7)
  - "Strassburn. (Or) Strakburg", undated (Box 7)
  - "The New Album of London", undated (Box 7)
  - "Half-Hours with the Early Explores. With Numerous Illustrations." by Thomas Frost. London, Paris, & New York: Cassell, Petter & Galpin, Belle Sauvage Works, undated (Box 7)
  - "Colonial Days. Being Stories and Ballads for Young Patriots, as Recounted by Five Boys and Five Girls in 'Around the Yule Log', 'Aboard the Mavis' and 'On the Edge of Winter'. Illustrated" by Richard Markham. New York: Dodd Mead & Company, 1879 - 1881 (Box 7)
  - "Stella. Fifth Edition." by Mary B. M. Toland. New York: James Miller, undated (Box 7)
  - "Five Weeks in a Balloon. The Jules Verne Library." by Jules Verne. London: Ward, Lock and Tyler, undated (Box 7)
  - "The Boy Voyagers Or The Pirates of the East. Every Boy's Library." by Anne Bowman. London: George Routledge and Sons, undated (Box 8)
  - "Biblioteca de Educacion. Manual de Logica que contiene lo sustancial que en esta asignatura deben aprender los estudiantes del primer ano de filosofi, por el Presbitero Don Juan Diaz de Baeza." by Don Juan Diaz de Baeza (multiple other authors). Madrid: Boix, 1842 (Box 8)
  - "Fasquelle's French Course on the Plan of Woodbury's Method with German. A New Method of Learning the French Langugae; Embracing Both the Analytic and Synthetic Modes of Instruction; Being A Plain and Practical Way of Acquiring the Art of Reading, Speaking, and Composing French. Revised and Improved. American Educational Series." by Louis Fasquelle. New York: Ivison, Phinney & Company (and) Chicago: S. C. Griggs & Company, circa 1860 (Box 8)
  - "History of Education in California. Thmese presented by the class in American Education at Stanford University, April and May 1894, under the charge of Will S. Monroe." by Will S. Monroe. Palo Alto (Box 8)
  - "The Pinks and Blues; Or, The Orphan Asylum. Illustrated. Rosa Abbott Stories." by Rosa Abbott. Boston: Lee & Shepard (and) New York: Lee, Shepard & Dillingham, circa 1870 (Box 9)
  - "The Story of A Bad Boy. Sixteenth Thousand Illustrated." by Thomas Bailey Aldrich. Boston: Houghton, Mifflin and Company (and) Cambridge: The Riverside Press, circa 1869 & 1877 (Box 9)
  - "Ungava: A Tale of Esquimaux-Land. With Illustrations by the Author. A Tale for Boys. The Boys' Own Library." by Robert Michael Ballantyne. London, edinburgh and new York: Thomas Nelson and Sons, undated (Box 9)
  - "A New Conversation Grammar of the German Language Adapted to the Use of Schools and Private Instruciton After the Practical and Theoretical Method of Robertson. Part I." by Dr. Augustus Boltz. Berlin: R. Gaertner (and) London: Asher & Co., 1872 (Box 9)
  - "Louis' School Days: A Story of Boys" by E. J. May. New York: D. Appleton & Company, 1852 (Box 9)
  - "Fighting Joe; Or, The Fortunes of a Staff Officer. A Story of the Great Rebellion." by Oliver Optic (William T. Adams). Boston: Lee and Shepard (and) New York: Lee, Shepard & Dillingham, circa 1865 (Box 9)
  - "Seek and Find; Or, The Adventures of a Smart Boy. Oliver Optic's Starry Flag Series." by Oliver Optic (William T. Adams). Boston: Lee and Shepard (and) New York: Lee, Shepard & Dillingham, circa 1867 (Box 9)
  - "Biblioteca de Educacion. Historia de la Edad Media. Tomo I." by Don Antonion Rosales (translator) (multiple other authors) Madrid: Boix, 1844 (Box 9)
  - "Album von Frankfurt AM Main" Frankfurt: Ph. Frey & Co., undated (Box 10)
  - "Baden Baden; von L. Meder, Kunst Verlag" Heidelberg, undated (Box 10)
  - "Ricordo Di Roma III." Roma: Luigi Monti. Edicola Piazza Colonna., undated (Box 10)
  - "Souvenir D'Amsterdam", undated (Box 10)
  - "Souvenir de Geneve" Geneve: F. Charnaux, undated (Box 10)
  - "The Locomotive Engineers' Journal and Proceedings. Vol. 3" by Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers. Fort Wayne, IN: Jones & Sons, Steam Book & Job Printers, 1869 (Box 10)
  - "Thor Valdsens Arbeider I." by Frue Kirke. E. V. Harboe, Kiobenhavn, undated (Box 10)
  - "The Boy Travellers in the Far East. Part Third. Adventures of Two Youths in a Journey to Ceylon and India with Descriptions of Borneo, the Philippine Islands and Burmah. Illustrated." by Thomas W. Knox. New York: Harper & Brothers, circa 1881 (Box 10)
  - "A Voice of Warning, and Instruction to All People Or, an Introduction to the Faith and Doctrine of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints. Eighth Edition." by Parley P. Pratt. Liverpool: F. D. Richards, 1854 (Box 10)
  - "Jerusalem" by M. W. Shapira. The British Museum, undated (Box 10)
  - "The Book of Docrine and Covenants of the Church of the Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints; Selected from The Revelations of God. Fifth European Edition. Stereotyped." by Joseph Smith. Liverpool: Brigham Young, 1866 (Box 10)
  - "Jungle, Peak, and Plain: A Boy's Book of Adventure. Illustrated." by Gordon Stables. London, Paris & New York: Cassell Petter & Galpin, undated (Box 10)
  - "Round-About Rambles in Lands of Fact and Fancy" by Frank R. Stockton. New York: Scribner, Armstrong & Co., 1872 (Box 10)
  - "The Wings of Courage. Stories for American Boys and Girls." by Marie E. Field (Illustrations by Lucy G. Morse) New York: G. P. Putnam's Sons, circa 1877 (Box 11)
  - "Young Folks' History of the United States. Illustrated." by Thomas Wentworth Higginson. Boston: Lee & Shepard (and) New York: Charles T. Dillingham, circa 1875 (Box 11)
  - "Elementos de Higiene Publica o Arte de Conservar la Salud de los Pueblos. Volume I. Segunda Edicion Revista, Aumentada con un Compendio de la Legislacion Sanitaria de Espana, y adornada con dos laminas finas (los planos de los lazaretos de Mahon y Vigo)" by D. Pedro Felipe Monlau. Madrid: Imprenta y Estereotipia de M. Rivadeneyra, 1862 (Box 11)
  - "Elementos de Higiene Publica o Arte de Conservar la Salud de los Pueblos. Volume II. Segunda Edicion Revista, Aumentada con un Compendio de la Legislacion Sanitaria de Espana, y adornada con dos laminas finas (los planos de los lazaretos de Mahon y Vigo)" by D. Pedro Felipe Monlau. Madrid: Imprenta y Estereotipia de M. Rivadeneyra, 1862 (Box 11)
  - "Elementos de Higiene Publica o Arte de Conservar la Salud de los Pueblos. Volume III. Segunda Edicion Revista, Aumentada con un Compendio de la Legislacion Sanitaria de Espana, y adornada con dos laminas finas (los planos de los lazaretos de Mahon y Vigo)" by D. Pedro Felipe Monlau. Madrid: Imprenta y Estereotipia de M. Rivadeneyra, 1862 (Box 11)
  - "Compendio de la Historia de Egipto, Desde los Tiempos Fabulosos Hasta Nuestros Dias." by M. Dey-Dussueil (translated from French to Spanish by D. Geronimo de la Escosura) Madrid: Imprenta de Don Vicente de Lalama, 1842 (Box 11)
  - "Words from the Poets. New Edition." by C. M. Vaugh. London: Macmillan and Co., 1877 (Box 11)
  - "The Dog Crusoe and His Master. A Story of Adventure in the Western Prairies. A Tale for Boys. The Boy's Own Library." by R. M. Ballentyne. London, Edinburgh, and New York: Thomas Nelson and Sons., undated (Box 12)
  - "Goat Land. A Story of Country Life. With Fifty-Two Illustrations." by the author of "The Life of A Bear" New York: Thomas Nelson and Sons (and) London and Aylesbury: Watson and Hazell, Printers, undated (Box 12)
  - "Geography for Beginners. Dr. Cornwell's Educational Series. Forty-Seventh Edition." by James Cornwell. London: Simpkin, Marshall & Co.; Hamilton, Adams, and Co. (and) Edinburgh: Oliver and Boyd, undated (Box 12)
  - "The Book of Common Prayer, and Administration of Sacraments, and other Rites and Ceremonies of the Church, According to the Use of the Protestant Episcopal Church in the United States of America: Together with the Psalter, or Psalms of David." by The Episcopal Church. Philadelphia: J. B. Lippincott & Co., 1857 (Box 12)
  - "Science Primers. VI. Physiology. With Illustrations." by M. Foster (edited by Professors Huxley, Roscoe and Balfour Stewart). New York: D. Appleton and Company, 1876 (Box 12)
  - "Peter the Whaler: His Early Life and Adventures in the Arctic Regions. Sixth Edition. With Illustrations by C. Duncan.) by William H. G. Kingston. London: Griffith and Farran, Successors to Newbery and Harris (and) Edinburgh: Murray and Gibb, Printers to Her Majesty's Stationery Officer., undated (Box 12)
  - "St. John, the Prisoner of Patmos" by Bishop Newman. New York: Hunt and Eaton, 1896 (Box 12)
  - "Prairie Days; Or the Girls and Boys of Osego" by Mary B. Sleight. New York: E. P. Dutton & Co., circa 1878 (Box 12)
  - "Mothers and Daughters: Practical Studies for the Conservation of the Health of Girls" by Tullio Suzzara Verdi. New York: J. B. Ford & Company, circa 1876 (Box 12)
  - "Routledge's Every Boy's Annual" by Various Authors, 1875 (Box 13)
  - "The Young Yachtsmen; Or, The Wreck of the Gipsy. A New Edition." by Anne Bowman. London and New York: George Routledge and Sons, 1879 or later (Box 13)
  - "Travels in Abyssinia and Nubia 1768-1773 to Discover the Source of the Nile. Second Edition, with Map and Illustrations." by James Bruce (James Bruce of Kinnaird, F.R.S.) Reduced from the Original Work by J. Illustrated by C. (?) A. Doyle. Edinburgh: Adam and Charles Black, 1873 (Box 13)
  - "The Story of Liberty. Illustrated." by Charles Carleton Coffin. New York: Harper & Brothers, circa 1878 (Box 13)
  - "Fairy Land, and Other Sketches for Youth: By the Author of Peter Parley's Tales." by S. G. Goodrich. Boston: James Munroe and Company, 1844 (Box 13)
  - "Young Folks' History of the United States. Illustrated." by Thomas Wentworth Higginson. Boston: Lee & Shepard (and) New York: Charles T. Dillingham, circa 1875 (Box 13)
  - "Lawrence's Adventures Among the Ice-Cutters, Glass-Makers, Coal-Minders, Iron-men, and Ship-Builders" by J. T. Trowbridge. Boston: Fields, Osgood & Co., circa 1870 (Box 13)
  - "Frank Before Vicksburg. The Gun-Boat Series. Books for Boys, by a Gunboat Boy." by Harry Castlemon. Philadelphia: Porter & Coates (and Cincinnati, OH: R. W. Carroll & Co., circa 1864 (Box 14)
  - "Frank in the Woods. The Gun-Boat Series. Books for Boys, by a Gunboat Boy." by Harry Castlemon. Philadelphia: Porter & Coates (and Cincinnati, OH: R. W. Carroll & Co., circa 1865 (Box 14)
  - "Frank on a Gun-Boat. The Gun-Boat Series. Books for Boys, by a Gunboat Boy." by Harry Castlemon. Philadelphia: Porter & Coates (and Cincinnati, OH: R. W. Carroll & Co., circa 1864 (Box 14)
  - "Frank on the Lower Mississippi. The Gun-Boat Series. Books for Boys, by a Gunboat Boy." by Harry Castlemon. Philadelphia: Porter & Coates (and Cincinnati, OH: R. W. Carroll & Co., circa 1867 (Box 14)
  - "Frank on the Prairie. The Gun-Boat Series. Books for Boys, by a Gunboat Boy." by Harry Castlemon. Philadelphia: Porter & Coates (and Cincinnati, OH: R. W. Carroll & Co., circa 1867 (Box 14)
  - "Frank the Young Naturalist. The Gun-Boat Series. Books for Boys, by a Gunboat Boy." by Harry Castlemon. Philadelphia: Porter & Coates (and Cincinnati, OH: R. W. Carroll & Co., circa 1864 (Box 14)
  - "Cross and Crescent; Or, Young America in Turkey and Greece. A Story of Travel and Adventure. Young America Abroad - Second Series." by Oliver Optic (William T. Adams). Boston: Lee and Shepard (and) New York: Lee, Shepard & Dillingham, circa 1872 (Box 14)
  - "Money-Maker; Or, The Victory of the Bsilisk. The Yacht Club Series. With Thirteen Illustrations." by Oliver Optic (William T. Adams). Boston: Lee and Shepard (and) New York: Lee, Shepard & Dillingham, circa 1873 (Box 14)
  - "Les Deux Petits Robinsons de la Grande-Chartreuse. Ouvrage Illustre de 69 Vignettes Sur pois par E. Bayard et H. Clerget. Cinquieme Edition. Bibliotheque Rose Illustree." by Jules Taulier. Paris: Librairie Hachette et C., 1879 (Box 14)
  - "Alexis the Runaway; Or, Afloat in the World. Rosa Abbott Stories. Illustrated." by Rosa Abbott (Mrs. Rosa Abbott Parker). Boston: Lee & Shepard, circa 1867 (Box 15)
  - "Jack of All Trades. Rosa Abbott Stories. Illustrated." by Rosa Abbott (Mrs. Rosa Abbott Parker). Boston: Lee & Shepard, circa 1867 (Box 15)
  - "Frank Among the Rancheros. The Rocky Mountain Series." by Harry Castlemon. Philadelphia: Porter & Coates (and Cincinnati, OH: R. W. Carroll & Co., circa 1871 (Box 15)
  - "Frank in the Mountains. The Rocky Mountain Series." by Harry Castlemon. Philadelphia: Porter & Coates (and Cincinnati, OH: R. W. Carroll & Co., circa 1868 (Box 15)
  - "Tales of the Sea. With Six Full-Page Illustrations." by William H. G. Kingston. Edinburgh and London: Gall & Inglis, undated (Box 15)
  - "The Sixth Reader." by Lewis B. Monroe. Philadelphia: Cowperthwait & Co., 1872 (Box 15)
  - "A Day of Fate." by E. P. Roe. Dodd, Mead and Company, undated (Box 15)
  - "The Holy Bible Containing the Old and New Testaments Translated Out of the Original Tongues Being the Version Set Forth A.D. 1611 Compared with the Most Ancient Authorities and Revised. Self-Pronouncing Edition with Reference. Clear Type Edition." New York: International Bible Agency, after 1885 (Box 16)
  - "Holy Bible", circa 1840 (Box 17)
  - "The Wise King. Written for the American Sunday-School Union, and Revised by the Committee of Publication." by American Sunday-School Union. Philadelphia: American Sunday-School Union, 1835 (Box 17)
  - "A Manual of Law, for the Use of Business Men: Containing, Alphabetically Arranged, the Legal Principles of Most Frequent Application to Ordinary Business Transactions, Together with References to the Authorities Sustaining Them." by Amos Dean. Albany: WM. & A. Gould & Co. (and) New York: Gould, Banks & Co., 1838 (Box 17)
  - "The World Beyond: Presenting Some of the Faces, Laws and Phenomena of the Great Hereafter, New-Church Popular Series No. 1" by John Doughty. Philadelphia: Swedenborg Publishing Association, 1882 (Box 17)
  - "A History of the United States of America, On a Plan Adapted to the Capacity of Youth, and Designed to Aid the Memory by Systematic Arrangement and Interesting Associations, Revised and Enlarged from the One Hundredth Edition. Boston School Book Depository." by Charles A. Goodrich. Boston: Jenks & Palmer, undated (Box 17)
  - "Hiram Golf's Religion, Or, the 'Shoemaker by the Grace of God' 29th Thousand. God is Love." by George H. Hepworth. New York: E. P. Dutton & Company, circa 1893 (Box 17)
  - "They Met in Heaven" by George H. Hepworth. New York: E. P. Dutton & Company, circa 1894 (Box 17)